Guide to the Eckard V. Toy Jr. Papers, 1920s-1995 RL.10160
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Eckard V. Toy Jr. papers
1920s-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Toy, Eckard Vance, Jr.
RL.10160
3.0 Linear Feet
Eckard Toy was an American history professor and scholar who studied the history of race, the Ku Klux Klan, and neo-Nazis in the United States, particularly in the Pacific Northwest. Collection includes Toy's research files and related materials on various extremist groups in the United States, particularly right-wing Christian extremists, the Ku Klux Klan, and Holocaust revisionists. Files are arranged by group or topic and at times include Toy's correspondence with various representatives. Notable groups include the Church of Jesus Christ Christian, various factions of the Ku Klux Klan, the German American National Political Action Committee (GANPAC), the Institute for Historical Review, and Christian Biblical America. Collection also contains Toy's research on Francis Yockey and Gordon Kahl. Materials from the IHR include two VHS tapes and one audiocassette on Holocaust revisionism.
Collection Overview
Collection includes Toy's research files and related materials on various extremist groups in the United States, particularly right-wing Christian extremists, the Ku Klux Klan, and Holocaust revisionists. Files are arranged by group or topic and at times include Toy's correspondence with various representatives. Notable groups include the Church of Jesus Christ Christian, various factions of the Ku Klux Klan, the German American National Political Action Committee (GANPAC), the Institute for Historical Review, and Christian Biblical America. Collection also contains Toy's research on Francis Yockey and Gordon Kahl. Materials from the IHR include two VHS tapes and one audiocassette on Holocaust revisionism.
Historical note
Eckard Toy was an American history professor and scholar who studied the history of race, the Ku Klux Klan, and neo-Nazis in the United States, particularly in the Pacific Northwest.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Eckard V. Toy, Jr. Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gift in 2014.
Right-wing extremists -- United States.; White nationalism -- United States; Racism -- United States; Neo-Nazis -- United States; Institute for Historical Review; Kahl, Gordon Wendell; German American National Political Action Committee; Ku Klux Klan (1915- )
- Research Files, 1
  - A-Albionic Consulting and Research newsletters, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Alert Americans Association, 1983 (Box 1)
  - America's Future, 1982 (Box 1)
  - American Council of Christian Churches (Carl McIntire), 1982 (Box 1)
  - American Independent Party, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Theology Correspondence Bible Course, 1981 (Box 1)
  - American Party newspapers, 1982 (Box 1)
  - American Party of Idaho, 1978 (Box 1)
  - American Youth Forum (Robert DePugh), 1982 (Box 1)
  - Angriff Press catalogs, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith reports on hate groups, 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Anti-Klan/anti-racist organizations, pamphlets, 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Aryan Crusaders for Christ, Winston-Salem, NC, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Aryan Youth Movement (John Metzger), 1980s (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Also referred to as White Student Union.
  - Benson, Ragnar: Mantrapping, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Boniface Press, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Burke, Emory: correspondence, 1988 (Box 1)
  - California Ku Klan Klan (Tom Metzger), 1980s (Box 1)
  - Canadian hate literature clippings, 1990s (Box 1)
  - CATO Institute: Revisionism: A Key to Peace, by Harry Barnes, 1980 (Box 1)
  - CAUSE Foundation (Canada, Australia, United States, South Africa, and Europe) mass mailings, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Center for Democratic Renewal, 1980s; 3 folders (Box 1)
    "Aryan Nations Far Right Underground Movement" report, "Ballot Box Bigotry" report, The Monitor issues
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, 1968-1990s; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Correspondence and newsletters
  - Christian Biblical America correspondence and newsletters, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Christian Nationalist Crusade catalogs, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Christian Patriot Defense League newsletters and publications, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
  - Christian Voice, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Christian Youth Corps, undated (Box 1)
  - Church of Israel catalogs, correspondence, and mass mailings, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Church of Israel, writings by Dan Gayman, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Church in the Valley of Jesus Christ Christian, British Commonwealth of Aryan Nations newsletters and correspondence, 1983 and undated (Box 1)
  - Church League of America (Maj. Edgar Bundy), 1980s (Box 1)
  - Church of Jesus Christ Christian/Aryan Nation pamphlets, 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Coalition for Human Dignity reports, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Committee of Ten Million (Independence, MO), 1980s (Box 1)
  - Committee to Free Patriots and Anti-Communist Political Prisoners, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Committee to Restore the Constitution (Col. Arch Roberts), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Conspiracy Digest (Alpine Enterprises), 1981 (Box 1)
  - Critique Journal mass mailings, undated (Box 1)
  - Cultural Reformation Movement, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Destiny Publishers (Identity Movement), 1980s (Box 1)
  - Dilys, Joseph, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Euro-American Alliance: The Talon, 1982 (Box 1)
  - From the Mountain, 1989 (Box 1)
  - From the North newsletters, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Full Disclosure newspaper, 1986 (Box 1)
  - GANPAC (German American National Political Action Committee) newsletters and correspondence, 1980s (Box 1)
  - H du B Reports, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Identity Directory, 1980s (Box 1)
    With other miscellany sent by Steve Goodyear
  - Independent Republican Association, Glen Cove, NY, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Information Digest (John Rees), 1982 (Box 1)
  - Institute for American Democracy, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Institute for Historical Review correspondence with Keith Stimely re: research on revisionist history, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Institute for Historical Review, 1980s-1990s; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Highlights of the 9th International Revisionist Conference VHS tape, 1989; 1 VHS tape (Box 2)
  - Highlights of the 10th International Revisionist Conference VHS tape, 1990 Oct.; 1 VHS tape (Box 2)
  - Introduction to Holocaust Revisionism audiocassette, undated, 1 audiocassette (Box 2)
  - K and N magazine, 1939 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Kahl, Gordon: reports, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Kingdom Seekers Ministry, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Keegstra: The Issues, The Trial, The Consequences, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Ku Klux Klan ephemera, 1920s-1930s (Box 2)
  - Ku Klux Klan catalogs, 1977 and 1981 (Box 2)
  - KKK/Aryan assorted newsletters, publications, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Report on the KKK in Canada, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Ku Klux Klan, Invisible Empire of the Knights of the KKK correspondence, 1983 and undated (Box 2)
    correspondence and clippings re: Bill Wilkinson
  - Ku Klux Klan, White Knights of Texas newsletters, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Last Call Ministries mass mailings, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Legal Eagle anti-tax, Pinckney, Michigan, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Liberation Movement of the German Reich: materials re: Manfred Roeder, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Liberty Bell miscellaneous publications, 1980s; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Liberty Lobby report on ADL, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Militia of Montana, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Mountain Church: "Birth of a Nation" and correspondence, 1989 (Box 2)
  - NAACP California conference, correspondence, 1980 (Box 2)
  - National Determination Party, 1982 (Box 2)
  - National Educator / National Education Association, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
  - National Institution for a Victorious America, 1981 (Box 2)
  - National Socialist Liberation Front, 1980s (Box 2)
    "Siege" and "Defiance"
  - National Socialist Movement newsletter and correspondence, 1983 (Box 2)
  - National Socialist Vanguard Report (Rick Cooper), 1987 (Box 2)
  - Nationalist Party of Canada, 1982 (Box 2)
  - National Socialist Party of America, 1980 (Box 2)
  - New Beginnings, 1986 (Box 2)
  - New Christian Crusade Church, 1983 (Box 2)
  - The New Patriot, 1970 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - New Odinist Fellowship, Inc., Crystal River, FL, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Omega Ministries, End-Times News Digest, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Omni Publications, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Have I been Foolish? essay by William Dudley Pelley, undated (Box 2)
  - Phoenix Books, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Pimmit Press, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Populist Party newsletters, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Preparedness Journal, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Promise Keepers Watch / Center for Democracy Studies, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Rajneeshpuram and the abuse of power, by T L Shay, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Resurgence newsletters, Amherst, NY, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Samaritan News, Dallas, OR, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1970s-1980s (Box 2)
  - Seraphim Press, CA, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Smith, Bradley, 1980s (Box 2)
    "Confessions of a Holocaust Revisionist" correspondence and excerpts
  - Southern National Party, Memphis, Tenn., 1983 (Box 2)
  - Sovereign Press catalog, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Survivalist sources, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Sword of Christ: White Christian Church of America, London, Arkansas, 1980s (Box 2)
  - United Front Against Fascism, 1990 (Box 2)
  - United Klans, UKA, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Western Foundation of Dualism: "Dragonfire", 1982 (Box 2)
  - Western World Press, 1982 (Box 2)
  - White Aryan Resistance (WAR), 1980s (Box 2)
  - White Student Union, Sacramento, CA, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Worldwide Church of God, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Yockey, Francis Parker, 1980s (Box 2)